Scientific Name -- Vicugna Pacos
Size – About 3’ at the shoulders, weighing 100-200lbs
Diet – Grass, Hay, and Grain
Domesticated for millennia primarily for their coats, alpacas are most common in South America at high elevations. While sometimes confused with llama, alpacas are smaller and rarely used as beast of burden. Instead, their hypoallergenic, flame-resistant hairs are woven into a variety of clothing. While alpacas do have a reputation for spitting, they are generally friendly towards humans and can even be house trained.