Этот атлантийский аркус был посвящен в герои. Как и обычные аркусы, он эффективен против пехоты и уязвим перед быстрыми юнитами, такими как кавалерия; но как герой, он также эффективен против мифических созданий. Все герои могут переносить реликвии.

All Atlantean Citizens were practiced in the use of at least one weapon. Those who showed skill with ranged weapons - slings, bows, javelins - were called into the ranks of the Arcus. The Atlantean Arcae were the first effective military use of ranged foot soldiers. Slings eventually fell into disuse and javelins became more feasibly wielded from horseback. The focused and deadly Arcus that emerged over time was a master of the bow and any number of Arcae fielded in battle gave their opposition great pause.