Атлантийские аркусы эффективны против пехоты и уязвимы перед быстрыми юнитами, такими как кавалерия. Как и все лучники, они более эффективны в составе больших групп.

All Atlantean citizens were practiced in the use of at least one weapon. Those who showed skill with ranged weapons - slings, bows, javelins - were called into the ranks of the Arcus. The Atlantean Arcae were the first effective military use of ranged foot soldiers. Slings eventually fell into disuse and javelins became more feasibly wielded from horseback. The focused and deadly Arcus that emerged over time was a master of the bow and any number of Arcae fielded in battle gave their opposition great pause.