Научное название — Alrovanda Ampelos Subsp. Xiros
Размеры — примерно 3 м в высоту
Рацион — хищное растение, питающееся грызунами и случайно забредшими путниками

Carnivorae catch and kill quickly, but must digest before snaring more prey. Heroes and ranged units can avoid a Carnivora's vines.

The Titan Oceanus gave several of his sacred Carnivorae to the Titaness Gaia as a gift. Carnivorae on land were easy to avoid if seen, but often, because they blended so well with their surroundings, unsuspecting prey blundered into them quite unawares and were ensnared to be digested gruesomely over the course of a week or more.