Научное название — Aldrovanda ampelos
Размеры — примерно 3 м в высоту
Рацион — хищное растение, питающееся рыбой и случайно проплывающими матросами

Carnivorae catch and kill quickly, but must digest before snaring more prey. Heroes and ranged units can avoid a Carnivora's vines.

Sacred to the Titan Oceanus, the carnivorous aquatic plant guarded his palace. Also called the Fangs of Charybdis, this plant was responsible for the disappearances of more vessels than the Sirens and Charybdis combined. Many aquatic Carnivorae were cultivated in the bays of Atlantis and along shipping channels to protect Atlantean trade. It was a punishable offense to sail into one of these sacred plants, though very few who ventured that close to a Carnivora survived to face punishment.