Научное название — Ursus Arctos
Вес — до 365 кг
Рацион — преимущественно коренья, фрукты и орехи. Реже — рыба и млекопитающие.

The brown bear is the second largest bear species in the world, after the polar bear. Although smaller than the grizzly and Kodiak of North America, the European brown bear once inhabited the entire continent except for a few northern islands (such as Ireland). Deforestation and human expansion have pushed them into small populations in Romania and the former Yugoslavia, and large populations in Scandinavia and Russia.

Brown bears are largely herbivorous, though they opportunistically feed on carcasses, fish and even anthills. Bears in cooler climates hibernate for several months, though those in Spain and Croatia may remain active all year. Little is known of brown bear social organization. They do not appear to be territorial and do not form pair bonds.