The primary Egyptian cavalry, Camelry are good at countering Cavalry and Siege Weapons, but are vulnerable to infantry.

Desert warriors of the Middle East employed camels mainly as dependable transport across the arid wastes of the region. Camels could carry two men in a pinch and reasonable loads. They had reasonable speed for short periods also. In addition, horses unfamiliar with camels shied away from them, making camelry particularly effective against horse-mounted troops.