The Chinese Castle is a fortified stronghold built mostly for defensive purposes. When units are garrisoned inside, they stay protected and contribute to the firepower of the Castle. The building can also be used to train units and research technologies that improve their effectiveness in battle.

Due to their need to defend and control large and often mountainous areas, the Chinese would perch their castles on mountain tops and often surround them with a massive fortified wall.