Siege weapons can destroy buildings, but are weak against other units, especially cavalry. Egyptians can also use Catapults to defeat enemy ships.

Catapults were invented by the Greeks for use as artillery on the battlefield or during a siege. By creating tension by pulling back large bow-like arms or twisting cordage made of hides or hair, a great throwing force could be achieved. Catapults could throw a stone weighing over 10 pounds to a range of nearly 1500 feet.