Научное название — Homo Equus
Размеры — более 2 м в длину, вес около 725 кг
Рацион — всеядный, любит вино

Half-man and half-horse, Centaurs are usually seen with torso and head of a man and the body of a horse, but different descriptions exist. They were notorious for showing up uninvited to outdoor celebrations (for a creature that large they seemed to have had trouble holding their liquor) and for abducting women, especially young maidens. Because of their drunkenness and inclination toward violence, most were driven to the mountains of Thessaly. Chiron, the centaur that educated Achilles was an exception. Centaurs are usually depicted carrying a bow.