Much controversy surrounds the construction of the great pyramids of ancient Egypt. How were they built? Why are the horizontal dimensions multiples of Pi? Ancient Egyptian architects and builders used rolling wheels to measure distances. It would have been a very consistent, reliable and efficient method to lay out the large dimensions of their grand constructions. Later Greek mathematicians gave a name to the distance a circle would roll in one complete revolution -- Pi.