Norse buildings were largely constructed of wood, stone and turf. Fierce winters required the buildings to have thick walls that would trap heat and steeply sloped roofs that would more easily shed heavy winter snows. An 11th century Norse farm was recently discovered in Newfoundland at L'Anse aux Meadows National Historic Site. It consists of three halls where between 80 and 100 people ate, worked, slept and socialized. Other buildings include two workshops and shelters for livestock.