Возраст — 26
Родина — Китай
Род деятельности — наследник Императора

Born as the rightful heir and successor to the legendary Emperor Yao, Danzhu was very much unlike is father. Vicious, wasteful, and spoiled, Danzhu was slowly deemed more and more unfit to the throne. Despite the bleak prospects, Yao perservered in trying to prepare his son and give him a chance to prove his worth by sending him on various expeditions. However, Danzhu merely sought to take advantage of these expeditions for his own benefit.
