Научное название — Capreolus Capreolus
Размеры — about 60 lbs.
Рацион — buds, leaves, ferns, grasses

"Deer" is used as a generic term for any hoofed animal with antlers, but also refers to specifc species within that group. Like all species within the group, except caribou, only male deer have antlers. The European or Western roe deer is a small deer native to Scandinavia and Russia. They live in small groups and are seasonally territorial.