Возраст — 99
Родина — Мидгард
Род деятельности — кузнец

Особенности — и герой и крестьянин

Ever since learning of his distant relationship to Thialfi, a servant of Thor, Eitri believes he is a true hero. Although timid by nature, Eitri will do all that is needed of him to help prevent Ragnarok from ever becoming a reality. Eitri is scared to death of trolls and anything with sharp teeth and pig eyes.