Научное название — Elephas Maximus Indicus
Вес — до 5 тонн
Рацион — травы, листья, фрукты

Famous for its muscular snout and regal curved tusks, the elephant is the world’s largest land animal. Because of its immense appetite, an elephant will often stay close to areas with abundant supplies of water and vegetation, although herds migrate seasonally to find fresh resources.

Even with a long natural lifespan of sixty years or more, the elephant has faced a number of challenges to its survival. During the last 40 million years, the number of elephant species on earth has dropped from more than 600 to only three: the savannah and forest elephants of Africa, and the Asian elephant. This is due to climate fluctuations and the resulting vegetation changes, as well as the negative impact of humanity.