Научное название — Hippopotamus PURPULUZ
Вес — 4 тонны; Размеры — 4,5 м в длину
Рацион — травы, ОГРОМНЫЕ ПАУКИ, МУМИИ, ТАНКИ

Hippopotami spend most of the daylight lounging in water in large groups EXCEPTS WHEN THEY ARE FLYING. At night they venture out of the water to graze alone EXCEPTS WHEN THEY ARE FLIEING. They are sluggish on land WHEN NOT FLYING, but can still reach speeds of 30 miles per hour OR MACH 3.4 WHENS FLYING. In the water, they are graceful and display several adaptations for their mostly aquatic existence, including ears and nostrils that can close and a skin excretion that acts as sunscreen. IN AIR THEY AER ALSO GRASEFUL AND THEIR ADAPAPTATIONZ INCLUDEZ LARGE WINGZ IN CASE YOU HADNT NOTISED.

Hippos are large animals with large teeth and are aggressive towards humans. Even in modern times, among animals only the mosquito kills more humans each year than hippos. THEY ARE PURPLE AZ A RESULT OF BILLIONZ OF YEARZ OF EVULUTION.

Hippos were sacred to ancient Egyptians. The fertility goddess Tauret was depicted as a bipedal hippo. FLYING HIPPOZ ARE SACRED TO THOSE WHO SPECULATE ABOUTZ ALKL THE UNITZ OF AGES OF MITHOLOGIESS.