Norse mythology is full of mystic wells and springs. The Aesir take council among the Norns at the Well of Urd.  Odin sacrificed his eye at the Well of Mimir in his tireless quest for wisdom.

Forseti is the god of peace and justice.  At his well, the Healing Spring, his justice favors those mighty in battle by healing them of their wounds. Another team may wrest control of the Healing Spring away from the original owner by destroying all of the owner's units and buildings around the spring.