Научное название — Atlas ekatocheri
Размеры — 4,5 м в высоту
Рацион — плотоядны, в основном люди

The Heka Gigantes are strong against human soldiers, sending them flying with their many-handed strikes. They are weak against heroes.

One hundred arms and fifty heads grew out of the shoulders of the Hekatonkheires. They were the sons of Oranos and Gaia and were so terrible that Oranos ordered them imprisoned in Tartarus. A fate he himself would suffer at the hands of his grandsons Zeus, Poseidon, and Hades.