You may build a limited number of Houses. Each House and Town Center supports a fixed number of population units (villagers, soldiers, boats, mythological creatures, and trade carts). No new units can be created above this limit.

When agriculture made possible a less nomadic lifestyle, humans began creating more permanent living quarters near their farms, rather than occupying transitory camp sites near hunting grounds or natural shelters like caves. Well built housing improved the quality and longevity of life.