Greek infantry are more expensive than those of other cultures, but they are also more powerful. The Hypaspist excels at fighting enemy infantry.

Alexander’s great army of conquest included three regiments of Hypaspists. These were apparently the best of his peasant infantry and of equal status and ability to his Foot Companions, most of noble blood. The Hypaspists were capable of fighting as traditional Hoplite infantry, or could switch to javelins and lighter armor for rapid movement in rough terrain. They were used to rapidly close with the enemy and distract them, allowing the Companion cavalry to hit the enemy from a side or the rear.