This Atlantean Turma has become a hero. Like all other Turmae, he is exceptionally good against archers and weak against all other units; but as a hero, he is more effective against myth units. Все герои могут переносить реликвии.

The training of the Atlantean Turma was very focused and dangerous requiring years to perfect. Both horse and rider had to be athletic, tough and fast. A veteran Turma could kill a bird in flight with a well-aimed javelin throw. The horses, descended from wild Atlantean stock, were no less exceptional. These horses were so prized that capturing even one from the Atlanteans in battle was considered great good fortune - even if the battle was lost. Many great bloodlines were founded in other regions by such captured Atlantean stock.