Scientific name -- Megaherpeton midgardii
Size -- about 60' long (but their father was about 7900 miles long!)
Diet -- whales, large fish

The original Jormundgard, of which these creatures are just the elvers (another word for baby eels), was a monstrous sea serpent and the offspring of Loki and the giant Angrboda. Odin threw the serpent into the seas of Midgard when it was small, but it grew so large that it could surround the earth by biting its own tail. During Ragnarok, Thor was fated to finally slay the serpent, but he would drown in the dying serpent's venom.