King Sahure of the Fifth Century is credited with establishing the first Egyptian navy. The ships were constructed in the city of Byblos, by Phoenicians who were the finest known shipbuilders. Like many Egyptian ships, these galleys could be sailed down the Nile and rowed back the other direction. Their 18 oars gave the Egyptian warships good manuverability, particularly over the non-rowed warships of Egyptian enemies, such as the "Sea Peoples." Egyptian galleys were equipped with rams, but combat typically consisted of boarding or archer fire. Egyptian ships had high bulwarks to protect against enemy missiles, and their own archers were trained in naval combat.