Научное название — Psychroteuthis Pelagii
Вес — более 27 тонн
Рацион — глубоководная рыба и ракообразные

A creature from the sea so large that on the surface it was mistaken for a chain of islands, the Kraken is found in Norse mythology. Seamen were often lost when they camped on what they thought was an island, only to be drowned when the creature swam back to the bottom of the sea. It had large tentacles and suckers with which it could seize large ships and drag them down. The Norse believe the Kraken would rise to the surface at the end of the world.