This Atlantean Contarius has become a hero. Like a regular Contarius, he is strong against archers and weak against infantry; but as a hero, he is much more effective against myth units. Все герои могут переносить реликвии.

Early Atlantean soldiers tamed and rode the wild horses that roamed across their island. These mounted soldiers were very successful in Atlantis's early conquests. But as Atlantis grew, farmland overtook wilderness and grazing became scarce. Cavalry all but disappeared from Atlantean tactics. Only an elite few rode horses into combat. Atlantean generals beaten in battle surrender their precious horses as a sign defeat.