Научное название — Borborodaes Megas
Размеры — более 15 м в длину. По слухам может достигать сотни метров в длину.
Рацион — ракообразные и моллюски

The word "Leviathan" ("twisted animal" in Hebrew) has been adopted to mean any gigantic monster, but was perhaps originally cited in the Bible and described in great detail. The leviathan was a fire-breathing creature that boiled the ocean when it swam near the surface. Its skin was covered with heavy armored plates like shields, and its belly was encrusted with broken pottery.

There is speculation that the word is a corruption of the seven-headed serpent "Lotan", a monster from Canaanite legend that was killed by Baal.