Научное название — Lacertilia
Вес — до 165 кг
Рацион — в основном насекомые, иногда овощи и фрукты

Lizards are reptiles of differing types and sizes that can be mostly found in warmer climates. Their strengths lie in their acute sight, agility, and the ability to climb and hold on to a variety of surfaces.

Their prey most commonly ends up being insects, or in case of larger lizards, small rodents and birds. 