Научное название — Phsyalia Mantalos
Размеры — щупальца до 30 м в длину!
Рацион — всеядны, в основном рыба

This monstrous siphonophore was actually a collection of creatures that cooperated to move and feed and fight. The 100 foot long tentacles produced a toxin that is almost as potent as cobra venom which the organism used to stun prey. For defense the creature could generate and direct an electric bolt, like a stroke of lightning. Physalia mantalos propelled itself by raising and lowering its crest to catch wind like a sail.