The Mining Camp is an Egyptian collection point for Gold. Place it adjacent to a Gold Mine that you wish to utilize. Improvements for mining may be researched at the Mining Camp. Empowering a Mining Camp with a Pharaoh increases the Gold you can gather.

The deserts surrounding ancient Egypt were rich in minerals, especially salt, copper, and gold. To harvest these resources, the Egyptians built mines, mainly open pit mines, often operated by slave labor.