Возраст — неизвестен
Родина — гора Хуаго
Род деятельности — король

The Monkey King, or Sun Wukong, was born out of a magic stone, which had been sitting on top of a mountain for a long time, drawing to itself the powers of earth and heaven.

When he came out, he had the physical appearance of a monkey, but the abilities of a god. He was able to travel at lightning speed and possessed an immense strength. With the powers, however, also came a sense of pride and cheekiness. 

After descending the mountain, Sun Wukong would soon become the king of the monkeys and animals he had befriended, and as he traveled, he would be quick to smugly take up any challenge. Bold and cheeky, he faced various lessons and often became reprimanded as a result for his audaciousness. In the end, however, the Monkey King learned how to attain enlightenment and was rewarded for his service and strength.