King Wuling of Zhao revolutionized Chinese warfare during the Han dynasty when he officially adopted the tactics and equipment of the Xiongnu people of the steppes: instead of stationing archers in chariots, he enacted military reforms to adopt the use of more versatile cavalry archers. He succeeded in emulating the battlefield successes of the Xiongnu, taking many cities of the neighboring Wuhu state before abdicating in favor of his son in 299 BC.