Научное название — Nymphae Thalassi
Размеры — сопоставимы с человеческими
Рацион — рыба, морские водоросли

Nereids may be trained at the Dock. They are a powerful Heroic Age myth unit capable of devastating attacks to ships.

The Nereids were the fifty nymphs of the sea. Many of them had important roles in mythology. They, like most nymphs, are beautiful creatures. The Nereids were often accompanied by hosts of sea creatures in their roving. But when the gentle nymphs went into battle, they rode fierce sharks who carried their mistresses tirelessly.