The Atlantean Oracle is slow, weak in combat and cannot see far while moving, but when standing still his line of sight grows to that of a tower.

Ancient Atlanteans relied heavily on the priest class for leadership and guidance. Oracles were priests who through a form of deep meditation could see beyond what normal sight would allow. Oracles were scouts and lookouts for Atlantean armies. It is debatable whether their great sight was granted by the Titans or the product of a deep attunement with their environment.