Научное название — Canis Lupus
Вес — 22-70 кг
Рацион — олени, лоси, овцы, мелкие млекопитающие

Historically, gray wolves could be found throughout the northern hemisphere, from the Arctic to the tropics. Habitat destruction and hunting have greatly reduced their ranges. They are highly social animals that live and hunt in packs of up to 36 individuals led by an alpha male and female. Unrelated immigrants may be adopted into a pack. Packs are generally territorial and patrol their domains against intruders. Except for the red wolf, all living wolves are considered to part of the C. lupus species. Domestic dogs, including feral subspecies such as dingos, are also classified as being wolves. Domestication, perhaps as many as 5 different times, has led to significant (but genetically irrelevant) differences between wolves and dogs.