The Ox Cart is a mobile drop site that can collect Food, Wood and Gold. The Ox Cart's mobility allows the Norse cultures to gather resources swiftly and efficiently. However, the slow-moving Ox Carts count against your population cap and are very vulnerable to attack.

The Norse Ox Cart in Age of Mythology is representative of the Norse hunting and gathering lifestyle that dominated their culture until agriculture and animal husbandry became predominant. The ancient Norse ranged far from their home bases for food and raw materials because their lands were not bountiful and their climate was harsh. Later, when they turned to raiding to increase their wealth, they tended to hit quickly, gather what was available, and move on. The Ox Cart represents the transitory nature of their resource gathering.