Научное название — Ailuropoda Melanoleuca
Вес — около 115 кг
Рацион — Бамбук

The Chinese name for the panda, da xiong mao, means “great bear-cat.” The panda is a member of the bear family, and generally resembles other bears in all but its unique black-and-white coloring. Its shaggy fur is white with black patches over the eyes, ears, and legs and a black band across its shoulders. The panda is native to forests high in the central mountains of China.
 
Since its sole source of food is the bamboo tree, a panda is specially suited to hold, crush, and then consume this tough plant. As if it were not unique enough, the panda has an enlarged sesamoid bone located on the forefoot. This bone holds the nearest tendon slightly further away from the joint than is normal, increasing its movement and enabling a special action similar to that of an opposable thumb. This allows for dexterous grasping. The panda’s teeth and jaws are designed to handle the job of grinding down bamboo shoots. They are bigger and broader than those of other bears, and the jawbones and cheek muscles are incredibly powerful.

160 pandas live in captivity, and their popularity has raised awareness of the animal’s plight in the wild. An estimated 1,600 pandas still live in their natural habitat, but only 60% of them live in protected forests. Saving pandas in the wild has become an important goal for conservationists, one that has sparked the imagination and support of the public. The panda has become an icon for endangered animal causes worldwide. 
