A Pharaoh empowering a foundation or building makes the <link="proto:Villager Egyptian">Laborers</link> working there build faster, gather faster and carry more.  A Pharaoh may also coax more <link="topic:Favor">Favor</link> from the gods by empowering a Monument.  The Pharaoh is a decent fighter, but it is his ability to heal units and devastating attacks on myth units that make him a good addition to an attacking army.  When a Pharaoh dies he is reborn amongst his people at a <link="proto:Settlement Level 1">Town Center</link>. Set Pharaohs can summon animals.

Egypt is separated into upper and lower Egypt and upper Egypt. At times during Egypt's history -- before King Menes, during the Hyksos invasion -- the unified nation had more than one ruler.