Оригинальное название — Бисе
Размеры — около 3 м в длину
Рацион — ограничивается золотом

Bearing a strong resemblance to a winged lion but with the head of a single-antlered dragon, Pixiu is a powerful mythical creature that wards off evil spirits and possesses an insatiable hunger for gold and silver. The last attribute led many to believe that the creature is able to attract wealth from all directions, and some literal depictions see the creature bring gold in its mouth.

Despite the association with fortune, Pixiu is also a very fierce creature with sharp fangs and a ferocious spirit in battle.