The Prodromos is good against other cavalry, such as Hippikon, Raiding Cavalry, Jarls and Contarius, but is weak against other types of units.

The Prodromoi were a light cavalry unit within the heavy Macedonian cavalry (Hetairoi or Companions) of Alexander the Great’s army. These men were armed with javelins or a shortened cavalry spear, plus a sword as their secondary weapon. They scouted for the army, but were used in battle with the heavier Companions if needed. They were particularly useful in battle during the pursuit of broken enemy troops that could be run down while fleeing.