Научное название — Homo Protos
Размеры — 2,1 м в высоту
Рацион — огонь, угольки, орлы

Prometheans are slow but have pretty good armor and a decent attack. When they are destroyed, two smaller Prometheans are formed from the clay of the first.

Prometheus was one of the few Titans who sided with the Olympians in the Titanomachy. He and his brother Epimetheus were tasked with the creation of humans. These first people were formed from clay and called Prometheans. Seeing their frail mortal forms struggle he gave his creations the gift of fire so that they could become strong. This angered Zeus and the god bound Prometheus to the side of a mountain where he was attacked and partially devoured every day.