Norse Raiding Cavalry are fast, but lack the strength of more expensive cavalry. Until they can train Huskarls in the Heroic Age, the Raiding Cavalry is the Norse's best response to archers or even Throwing Axemen.

Mounted warriors were especially suited for striking enemies quickly and without warning, often where most unexpected. Cavalry used as raiders were difficult to defend against because they could hit anywhere and disappear quickly. They were good for disrupting economies, looting or destroying goods, and doing a lot of damage. They were not equipped with heavy armor and weapons, because speed was their strength. They usually were not expected to fight in battle against enemy troops.