Научное название — Corvus Corax
Размеры — 60 см в длину, размах крыльев 1 м
Рацион — насекомые, семена, падаль, яйца

Huginn and Munnin are Odin's Ravens. They fly around the world, bringing back information. If they are killed, they will eventually re-form back at Odin's Temple.

Odin, the chief god of Asgard, was blinded in one eye. To compensate and keep aware of all that is happening in the nine worlds, each morning he sends out his two ravens, Huginn (thought) and Munin (memory), who see everything. In the evening, they fly home and perch on his shoulders, and whisper into his ears all that they saw.