The Fanatic is an expensive, late unit that is good against all other normal units and is vulnerable to units that are good against infantry like Toxotes or Throwing Axemen.

War cultists devoted to one Titan or another presented a great threat to the ruling priest class of early Atlantis - they were powerful, destructive and bowed to no law but their own. After the Titans were imprisoned some groups of cultists, still eager for blood but aware of their sudden vulnerability, organized under the banners of Atlantis. They were the Fanatics - they fought with two swords, disdaining the protection of a shield.