The Greek Scout is fast and has a good <link="topic:line of sight">line of sight</link>, but is weak in actual combat. Although you cannot train additional Katascopi, better scouts, such as Pegasi, are available later.

The name of this unit is found in the Bible and the interpretations of its meaning vary from explorer, spy, and scout. The Greeks used the word to refer to Romans exploring Greek lands, perhaps in preparation of the coming Roman conquest.