Возраст — 32
Родина — Карнак
Род деятельности — разбойник и ассасин

Worshipper of Set, desert shadow, poisoner and assassin - Kemsyt is a deadly enemy and a loyal ally. Kemsyt hungers for power but lacks the strength to inspire and lead others. Still, his network of information and resources more than make up for his wheedling nature and cowardice. Kemsyt and Amanra are old enemies who have fought many times, but Kemsyt has always managed to escape.