Возраст — 32
Родина — Яосюй
Род деятельности — местный старейшина

Shun had a difficult life from an early age, living in poverty and being forced to do a lot of hard work. It was through his compassionate nature and exceptional leadership skills that he gained a strong reputation and a large following. Stories of his kindness and accomplishments, where Shun had settled fights and brought prosperity to numerous villages, had reached even the ears of Emperor Yao. As he knew he would soon be looking for a successor, Emperor Yao chose to offer Shun a position in the court so that he could test both his skills and his heart.