At the Stable, Greek players may build mounted units, improve the quality of these units, and research improvements to make them more effective.

Mounted warriors brought new dimensions to war and combat. They could move quickly as raiders and on the battlefield. In pursuit they could ride down retreating enemies. Men charging on large animals were terrifying to men on foot. The rise in importance of mounted warriors created demand for large numbers of horses, which were bred and maintained at the Stable. Mounted warriors trained at the Stable, as well, learning the skills of fighting from horseback.