Научное название — Eudocimus Terribilis
Размеры — размах крыльев составляет 5,40 м
Рацион — хищники, любит также и домашний скот

The Stymphalian Bird is a formidable Heroic Age myth unit. Only ranged units and buildings can attack it - ranged heroes are the strongest against the birds of Stymphalos.

For his sixth labor, Heracles slew the Stymphalian Birds. These birds were aggressive and hunted in flocks, much like lions or wolves. They ravaged the countryside around their lakeside nesting grounds, killing and carrying off livestock and occasionally children. They had very keen senses and especially keen hearing. Heracles used their keen hearing against them when, instead of venturing into their dangerous nesting grounds, he stood on a mountain top and clashed a pair of god-crafted brass krotala (castanet-like noise makers). It made such a racket that the birds could not bear to stay near and as they flew away, Heracles shot them with his bow.