Научное название — Canis Terribilis
Размеры — 3 м в длину
Рацион — плотоядны, предпочиают человечину

These frighteningly destructive creatures are the offspring of Nyx and Cerberus. Nyx was a very ancient god of Night and the daughter of Chaos. Cerberus was the three-headed dog, a guardian of the Underworld. Oranos banished these creatures to Tartarus to rid himself of their ghastly presence, but also because he could not control them. They came when he called, but obeyed no commands thereafter.