This ancient Temple represents one of the great archeological mysteries of the ancient Atlanteans, for it pre-dates most Atlantean written history, and is located deep in the heart of the Egyptian ancestral lands. The fact that it honors Kronos many centuries before the Atlanteans were thought to begin their worship of that ancient entity has ignited fierce debates among Atlantean scholars and scribes for centuries. The Temple is an impressively constructed stone structure with the extraordinary characteristic of resisting Kronos's time-shifting powers. Additionally, although far from invulnerable to enemy attacks, the Ancient Temple of Kronos seems to be blessed with a unique protective aura, preventing it from being destroyable by its owners.