Оригинальное название — Циньлин Бинмаюн 
Размеры — 1,8 м в высоту (спешившись)
Рацион — пыль

Soldiers of the Terracotta Army are a formidable force loyal to the first Emperor of China. When the emperor passed away, a ceremonial burial was held and an army of over 8000 clay soldiers was sealed in the emperor's tomb in order to protect him in his afterlife. Each soldier is equipped with a range of weapons and the ranks include both infantry units and units on horseback.