Научное название — [невозможно классифицировать божество]
Размеры — 30 м в высоту
Рацион — молитвы и подношения

Titans emerge from Tartarus to wreak havoc upon the earth. They are very dangerous to anything near them, soldiers, civilians, buildings - they are the creative and destructive forces of nature and thought.

The Titans ruled over the cosmos before the times of the Olympians and other newer gods. They were forerunners, the first great ones, overcome by their offspring and cast into the remoteness of Tartarus.

They governed phenomena and concepts like time, daring, and the unseen as well as forces of nature like the Sun, Earth, and Sky. Other cultures had their progenitor gods - Titans after a fashion - like Ymir, the ancient frost giant of Norse mythology, or Geb and Nut, early Egyptian gods who represented Earth and Sky.