Trading ships of all kinds were requisitioned by rulers when they wanted to move armies overseas because trading ships had the necessary cargo capacity. Warships of the ancient age were not good transports because they were usually very narrow rowing galleys with little storage space, and built for speed. An invading army needed to transport not only soldiers, but weapons, tents, dry food, wine, and livestock.