This Destroyer has become a hero. Like other Destroyers, he is very effective against buildings and weak against swifter ranged units; but as a hero, he is more effective against myth units. Все герои могут переносить реликвии.

Armies attacking Atlantean colonies found their inhabitants far from defenseless - most notably the trident-wielding shore fishermen. These fishermen organized to defend Atlantis's far flung colonies. In later years the became an elite unit of Royal Guard - the Destroyer. The Destroyers have a long standing rivalry with the main line of Atlantean infantry - the Murmillo - over who has better served Atlantis.