Научное название — Vetenne Troll
Размеры — примерно 3 м в высоту
Рацион — камни, коренья, люди

Trolls are dim-witted, man-eating creatures that live in caverns beneath hills and mountains. They are allies of the giants, and will fight against the gods during Ragnarok. Trolls are strong, and have long lifespans, but are not known for their beauty. Trolls could be turned to stone if exposed to daylight. Some are known to steal women and children, and might leave a changeling in exchange for a kidnapped child. Some trolls had magical powers, particularly divination of the future.