“The war chariots rattle, war horses whinny, and each of you has a bow and quiver at his belt.” – Du Fu, “A Song of War Chariots.”

Charioteers were some of the most prestigious and effective soldiers in ancient Chinese armies. The platform of a chariot allowed archers and spearmen a fast but stable platform from which to wield their weapons. However, these platforms lacked maneuverability, and the chariot declined with the gradual introduction of steppe cavalry tactics, vanishing almost entirely from the battlefield by the 4th century BC.