The War Chariot was an ancient vehicle used for attacking and pursuing enemies in battle. It is believed to have been invented by Xi Zhong, and for a long time the chariot revolutionized battles, allowing archers and soldiers with dagger axes very high mobility. Apart from offering a superior form of attack for ranged units, the chariots also served military commanders, giving them better control over large armies. 

The chariot's glory came to a halt when cavalry units took over and nomadic mounted archery became more effective.