The son of the Titan Lapetus, Prometheus was born a mortal. He shaped humankind out of water and clay (and Athena breathed life into the form). After siding with Zeus against the Titans, he tricked the king of the gods into taking animal bones as sacrifices, leaving the good meat for humans. In spite, Zeus removed fire from the world, bringing great suffering to all. To relieve the people he had created, Prometheus stole fire from the Sun and gave it back to the world. In retaliation, a furious Zeus sentenced Prometheus to be chained to a rock for 30,000 years, while an eagle daily tore out his liver (which grew back each night). By giving warning to Zeus of a prophecy of his downfall, he won a reprieve and was allowed to trade his mortality to Chiron (doomed to an eternity of agony) and thereafter joined the immortals on Olympus.