A daughter of Ra, Bast was the goddess of the cat, considered a sacred animal in ancient Egypt. She was usually associated with the moon, perhaps because cat eyes can shine in moonlight. A special necropolis at her cult center in Bubastis held huge numbers of mummified cats. Together, Bast and the lioness-headed Sekhmet killed the great serpent Apep that tried to swallow Ra and turn the world into darkness.