Egyptians were buried in tombs. People of lesser importance might be buried together in large groups, while aristocrats, priests, and pharaohs had their own private tombs for their families. The most powerful pharaohs were enshrined in pyramids, or in massive caves like those at Karnak. Tombs of the wealthy were carefully hidden and fitted with false chambers and concealed doors to discourage thieves. While few important tombs escaped robbers, that of Tutankhamen was discovered in 1922 virtually intact and yielded a wealth of treasure, over 3500 items in all.

“The Osiris Ani, whose word is truth, saith: I am the serpent Sata whose years are infinite. I lie down dead. I am born daily. I am the serpent Sa-en-ta, the dweller in the uttermost parts of the earth. I lie down in death. I am born, I become new, I renew my youth every day.”

-– the Papyrus of Ani