Artemis calls forth the wrath of nature in a mighty Earthquake. Every unit in the area is affected, though enemies take more damage, and buildings are hurt much more than units. Farms take very little damage.

To unleash the devastation, left click on the Earthquake icon at the top of the screen, then left click where you want the center of the Earthquake to be.  You must have <link="topic:line of sight">line of sight</link> to target Earthquake.