Typhon was a fire-breathing monster that dripped venom from his eyes. The battle between the gods and Typhon was so destructive that most of life on earth was killed. In the end, Typhon hurled Mount Aetna at Zeus, but Zeus struck it with a hundred well-aimed thunderbolts and pinned Typhon beneath the rubble. The monster was never entirely killed, though, which is why Mount Aetna still rumbles with earthquakes and lava. Typhon had many offspring with the equally monstrous Echidna, including the Chimera.