Oracles studying the mysteries of Kronos learned methods of meditation that sent them visions much more quickly. By slipping into the future they could see more clearly, more quickly than other Oracles. As they advanced in their studies and drew further and further away from their normal time, these Oracles lost the ability to communicate their visions. Eventually they slipped entirely away, lost to their visions of the future.