As the smith of the Greek gods, Hephaestus forged many great items for the other gods, such as the thunderbolts of Zeus, Aegis Shield, arrows of Eros, chariot of Helios and armor of Achilles. He even helped to create the first woman, Pandora, of clay. Hephaestus also created items used against the gods when he was wronged, such as a throne that held Hera prisoner when she cast him out of Olympus for being so ugly, and a chain-link net used to trap his wife, Aphrodite, when he suspected her of cheating on him with Ares.