The invasion of the Hyksos at the end of the 14th Dynasty spurred the peaceful Egyptians to organize what had, to that point, been a rather informal army. The Pharaoh often led his armies into battle. The chain of command ran from the Pharaoh and princes to other nobles and officers, down to the “Greatest of Fifty." The Greatest of Fifty commanded fifty soldiers, one of four such groups under the command of a Standard Bearer. Soldiers under a Standard Bearer all carried the same arms and armament.