This Classical Age God Power creates a pool of healing water to seep up from the ground. Nearby allied units are healed of their wounds. Units that are standing still will heal faster than those who are moving or attacking.

The Healing Spring cannot be destroyed. However, be careful; if an enemy has more units near the area than you do, then the Healing Spring will belong to them and will heal their units. The Spring may change hands many times.

To call forth the healing waters, left click on the Healing Spring icon, then left click where you want to place it.  You must have <link="topic:line of sight">line of sight</link>  to target this God Power and it requires a large space.