Sea travel was a terrifying prospect for people of the ancient world. From mythical monsters such as the Greek Scylla or the Norse Kraken, to more mundane yet equally terrible maelstroms and icebergs, deadly dangers lurked in every ocean. But for rulers who were willing to invest the time and resources in a powerful fleet, such as King Minos of Crete, the sea offered many opportunities to gain an advantage over their rivals.