"Hekate then gave her infusion to Helios for his help in finding Persephone. Helios, renewed daily, had no need of this restorative and gave it to his father, Hyperion. Hyperion, far-sighted and all-seeing, smeared it upon the eyes of worthy mortals in their sleep. When these favored mortals awoke to sight and consciousness they found themselves rejuvenated."

-- Voices of the Oracles, the Lay of Ioleta