Armory mail upgrades affect the hack armor of all human soldiers, heroes, and ships: those trained at the Academy, Barracks, Military Barracks, Counter Barracks, Longhouse, Dock, Migdol, Fortress, or Hill Fort. They do not affect myth units or siege weapons. Hack armor protects a unit against hack attacks, which are generally hand-to-hand attacks such as swords and axes. The armor percentage is the amount by which the attack is reduced.