The Titan Theia, goddess of sight, ruled over Lemuria, the most loyal and advanced of Atlantean colonies. The Lemurians were tall and lithe, but were best known for their keen vision - a boon from their patron goddess. They were employed as scouts alongside Oracles for much of the Atlantean empire. The island of Lemuria was destroyed when the brother giants Ephialtes and Otus piled up mountains to reach Olympus, including the mountainous Lemuria.