Hera's God Power calls down a storm of lightning bolts that strike all enemy units in the area. In addition, the bolts may strike buildings or trees, but do much more damage against units. Quick enemies may be able to escape the storm, which covers a large area but does not move.

To call this mighty storm, left click on the Lightning Storm icon at the top of the screen, then left click where you want the storm to strike.  You must have <link="topic:line of sight">line of sight</link> to the targeted area.