This Heroic Age God Power summons a swarm of locusts that will destroy enemy Farms or Fishing Ships. Because both of these are expensive to establish, you can strike a blow against an enemy economy. The Locusts cannot be attacked, and do only minor damage to Villagers.

To plague your enemies with locusts, left click on the Locust Swarm icon, then left click it near where you want the locusts to swarm.  You must have <link="topic:line of sight">line of sight</link> to the area to target the swarm.