The skill of masonry arose in diverse areas, including those with good building stone and those with access to mud for making bricks. In ancient Egypt the skill was prized for constructing grand monuments and buildings. In ancient Greece the skill was required first for mountain citadels that protected agricultural valleys below. Then the Greeks turned to great temple, building, and defensive wall construction.