Tanngnjostr ("Teeth-grinder") and Tanngrisnir (“Teeth-barer”) were the names of the two goats that drew Thor’s chariot. Every night, if he wished, Thor could slaughter and eat these two for dinner. If he saved and buried their bones, the two goats would be fully restored when he awoke in the morning.

“She set forth salvers full, adorned with silver, on the table game and pork, and roasted birds. In a can was wine; the cups were ornamented. They drank and talked; the day was fast departing, Rig would counsel give to them both.”

-- The Poetic Eddas, The Lay of Rig