Theia, wife of Hyperion and mother of the sun, moon, and dawn, was the Titan most interested in learning from the upstart Olympians. Poseidon had much to teach his aunt, most importantly a method for breeding the finest steeds the world had ever seen. Whether Theia stole Poseidon's knowledge of horses or Poseidon simply volunteered to help the Atlanteans is unclear - but Poseidon's secret now belongs to the followers of Theia.