This Mythic Age God Power transforms your Pharaoh into the falcon-headed, lightning-wielding Son of Osiris. This unit has all the powers of a normal Pharaoh, such as countering Myth Units, healing and empowering, but is much more powerful in combat. He is under your control and lasts until killed. He cannot be healed. If he is killed, you will regain a normal Pharaoh.

Guard the Son of Osiris carefully; he will almost certainly become your enemy’s favorite target.

To turn your Pharaoh into a demigod, left click on the Son of Osiris icon at the top of the screen, then left click on your Pharaoh.  If you cannot locate your Pharaoh, use the banner button at the top right of the screen to center your view on him.