The swine array, or svynfylking, was a formation used by the Vikings and originally credited to Odin. Men would form a triangle, with the most heavily armored warriors in front, and perhaps archers in the rear ranks. The array could position spears against charging cavalry, or move forward to drive a wedge through enemy ranks. The array could be used alone, or in multiples with the rear ranks connecting to form a zig-zag frontage.