The Norse had many splendid horses throughout their mythology.  Svaldifari, the horse that built the walls of Asgard.  Skinfaxi and Hrimfaxi, who drew the Sun and Moon across the skies.  Grani, Sigurd’s horse, a son of Sleipnir – Grani feared nothing, not even fire and was “the best of all horses.” 

”Three troops of maidens;
though one maid foremost rode,
bright, with helmed head.
Their horses shook themselves,
and from their manes there sprang
dew into the deep dales,
hail on the lofty trees,
whence comes fruitfulness to man.
To me all that I saw was hateful.”

-- The Poetic Eddas, The Lay of Helgi Hiorvard´s Son