The Titan Rheia turns the heart of an enemy, converting it to your side. Rheia was betrayed by Kronos when he ate all of their children after learning that one of them would be his downfall. Rheia had secretly fed Kronos a swaddled rock, saving one of her children, the infant god Zeus. Zeus grew to adulthood, and after freeing his brothers and sisters he imprisoned his father Kronos in the deepest parts of Tartarus. Betrayal surrounded Rheia and she keenly understands its power.

To steal the allegiance of an enemy, left-click the Traitors icon, and then right-click the unit you wish to convert. This is very powerful when used on expensive myth units.