Set's God Power grants you brief <link="topic:line of sight">line of sight</link> to any part of the map, even if you have not explored there.

To invoke Vision, left click on the Vision icon, then left click anywhere on the map that you wish to see. Vision is best targeted on areas of the <link="topic:black map">black map</link>, especially when you learn something about where and what your enemy is building. Vision has another somewhat sneaky use. Because it can be targeted anywhere on the map, you can use Vision to give you <link="topic:line of sight">line of sight</link> long enough to target another God Power without having to rely on a fragile scout to make it into position.