Skadi was a great huntress, traveling her icy home of Thrymheim on snowshoes and carrying a bow with which she brought down much game.  After her stormy and eventually dissolved marriage to the Aesir Njord, she married Ull, the god of justice, skiing and agriculture.

“A seventh I will sing to thee. If on a mountain high frost should assail thee, deadly cold shall not thy carcase injure, nor draw thy body to thy limbs.”

-- The Poetic Eddas, The Lay of Hyndla